Felipe de Moraes Modesto

CAREER SUMARY

I have been working as a Software Developer in the Game Industry since 2011. During my career, I have implemented games and business applications for multiple platforms. For the past four years, I have also taken a management role, coordinating programmers and designer teams to ensure asset quality and compliance to project scope. I also have experience with clients having worked with some of Brazil's biggest corporations. I currently reside in Ottawa and am a permanent resident of Canada.

WORK EXPERIENCE

2011-2018 - Game Developer & Creative Director - Fira Soft Ltd.

Programmer & Production Lead (2011-2014) Programmer & Creative Director - Working Remotely (2014-2018)

• 2015-2017 - Teaching Assistant - Software Engineering - Android - uOttawa

TECHNICAL EXPERTISE

Programming

C++, C#, Python, Lua, Java, JavaScript, R, Linux Shell, SQL

Technologies

Unity3D, Mobile Development, Corona SDK, Android Studio IceScrum, SQlite, Google Analytics, rStudio, ADB, OBS

Process

Scrum (IceScrum), Git/Mercurial (GitHub / Bitbucket / Gitlab), GDD

PROJECTS & PUBLICATIONS

SEVeN - ICN Distributed Network Communication Simulator - OMNet++

C++ Roles: Architecture model, protocol stack implementation and debugging, Python data analysis, production of technical reports & other academic material

- Kriophobia (In Development) Survival Horror PC / PS4 Unity3D
- C# Roles: Feature programming, project management, production validation, asset validation, design documentation production, debugging
- NeuroVR In-surgery Cognitive Evaluation Tool PC / SteamVR Unity3D
- C# Roles: Project management, client interaction, feature programming, debugging, interface/usability design, patient evaluation metric design
- Autotrac SVOne Vehicle Tracker Android Native Android

Java Roles: Project management, feature programmer

Move-it! Charades - Virtual Board-Game - iOS / Android - Corona SDK

Lua Roles: Lead designer and programmer, core feature implementation, UI/UX design, publishing and maintaining store presence, game content production, client support

Wikinarua - Cartography-based Social Media - Android - Native Android

Java Roles: Feature Programmer

Other Custom Mobile-centric Projects for Clients - Unity, Corona, Android

Lua Roles: Varied roles associated with the positions of creative director and programmer, C# feature implementation, client management, production management, game design, Java documentation production

Multiple papers published in Academic Conferences and Journals

LaTeX Roles: Academic research proposal, implementation, analysis and document production Python Plase access google scholar page for a mostly complete list of publications

EDUCATION

- 2014-2018* PhD in Computer Science University of Ottawa
- 2011-2014 Master of Computer Science University of Brasilia (Brazil)
- 2007-2011 Bachelor in Computer Science University of Brasilia (Brazil)

CONTACT

- @ felipe@modesto.io
- +1 613 883 2898
- Ottawa ON, Canada
- in /femodesto

Career Interests

- **◆ Software Developer**
- **◆ Programmer**
- ◆ Game Developer
- ◆ Production Lead

BIO

Master of Computer Science

Language Skills

English
Portuguese
French
Spanish

Interests

- Data Analysis
- Automation
- Networks
- Graphics
- Innovation

Personal Interests

- Board-games
- Photography
- Mech. Keyboards
- Plotting Graphs
- Curious Facts

Personal Traits

- Team Player
- Leadership
- Problem-Solver
- Multi-tasker
- Perfectionist

SOCIAL MEDIA

github: felipemodesto twitter: felipemodesto

More details available at:

www.modesto.io